

Saint Petersburg, Russia

 \square (+7) 911-226-4992 | \square zhukovsd@gmail.com | \square zhukovsd | \square zhukovsd | \square zhukovsd |

Summary.

Software architect with 11 years of professional development experience. My position in the projects is usually a combination of architect, team lead and fullstack developer roles. I mainly focus on Java/Kotlin stack and DevOps/cloud technologies, but also have professional experience in Desktop and Web development. My passion is to start projects from the drawing board and deliver production ready solutions.

Skills _

Cloud services AWS (EKS, Keyspaces, DynamoDB), DigitalOcean (DO Kubernetes)

DevOps Kubernetes, Docker, Bash, CI/CD Services (Jenkins, CircleCI)

Backend development Java (Core, Spring Boot, Spring Data), Kotlin Web development Javascript 2015 (ES6), Webpack, SCSS/LESS Databases SQL, MongoDB, DynamoDB, Cassandra

Education

ITMO State University

Saint Petersburg, Russia

B.S. IN INFORMATION SYSTEMS AND TECHNOLOGIES

2007 - 2012

Experience _____

Code Partners Remote

SOFTWARE ARCHITECT / FULLSTACK DEVELOPER

- · Joined the company as a Senior Developer to work on various outsourcing projects. Later switched to Architect/Lead position to develop startup projects initiated within the company
- · As an architect, I'm involved in designing project requirements, solution architecture, setting up and managing cloud infrastructure and CI/CD
- · As a lead, I interview and onboard team members, delegate tasks and review the results
- As a developer, I design and implement parts of the system

Upwork Remote

FREELANCER 2016 - 2017

- My Upwork profile (currently private)
- Average project rating 5.00/5.00
- 20 projects in different areas:
 - Java
 - · Javascript/jQuery
 - Windows and MacOS installers
 - · Various desktop projects: launcher and installer for a MMO game, custom Chromium build, visual components for Delphi VCL

VBrand Remote

FULLSTACK DEVELOPER

Mar. 2017 - May 2017

- Implemented a screen capturing system (PowerShell, FFmpeg)
- Designed and developed a client-server application for video processing (cutting/merging/converting). RESTful API; Backend Java, FFmpeg; Frontend - Javascript, Bootstrap, ¡Query

SERGEY ZHUKOV · CV **DECEMBER 11, 2021**

ITVA Saint Petersburg, Russia

 DESKTOP DEVELOPER
 2010 - 2017

- Lead developer on a number of projects:
 - Native Windows applications
 - Cross-platform applications for Windows and MacOS
 - Web services
 - Libraries for internal usage within a team (internationalization library, persistent settings library)
- Was responsible for development and release of more than 10 software products
- · Used technologies:
 - Programming languages: Delphi, C++, Javascript
 - UI frameworks: VCL, Firemonkey, Skinbuilder, Sciter, CEF
 - · Libraries and databases: libtorrent, bass, MySQL, FireDAC, SQLite

Notable work projects _

Cloud logging solution

KOTLIN, SPRING BOOT, KUBERNETES, DYNAMODB

2021 - current

- Cloud logging tool, allowing developers to collect logs from the instances of their applications, which may be backend or desktop apps, and then inspect them
- The project is currently in the R&D phase, I work on formalizing functional requirements, choosing technologies and building the prototype

DevOps marketplace

JAVA, SPRING BOOT, PHP, KUBERNETES, DOCKER, JENKINS

2019 - current

- DevOps marketplace, allowing developers to sell their products and support to the customers. A key feature of the project is programmatic integration with DevOps platforms, such as Jenkins
- My role:
 - Design functional requirements, UI mockups
 - Develop parts of the system backend services, web application
 - Delegate tasks to designers and developers
 - · Manage project infrastructure cloud environments (Kubernetes) and CI/CD pipelines (Jenkins)

An application for processing video content

JAVA, JAVASCRIPT, BOOTSTRAP

2017

- A client-server application for processing (cutting/merging/converting) video content. Typical usage is to create highlights clip from a show or
 to cut out ads from a broadcast record
- · Architecture:
 - Backend Java, FFmpeg
 - Frontend Javascript, Bootstrap, jQuery
- · Backend service exposes RESTful API which serves requests from web app UI views

Loviotvet.ru

DELPHI 2010 - 2012

- Smart calculator for solving and simplifying math expressions and equations
- Self-implemented solving engine based on reverse polish notation builds a simplifications tree which allows displaying a solution in step-bystep fashion
- Supported math operations:
 - Common and decimal fraction operations
 - Polynomial operations including division
 - Solving linear and square equations
- · A web service based on solving engine exposes RESTful API and serves requests from mobile clients and web application
- Freeware desktop, mobile and web clients were released for CIS market. Mobile clients have 500k+ installs, the service app served more than 12 millions of requests

Self-motivated projects

Typing test GitHub project

KOTLIN, SPRING, ES6, PUGJS, WEBPACK, CIRCLECI, DOCKER SWARM

2018

- Running instance of the app http://88.99.12.213/
- A simple 1-minute typing speed test with frontend built with ES6/Pug.js. Each test result gets submitted to the backend (built with Kotlin/Spring)
 which responds with player's placement and stores typing speed characteristics (characters per minute, typos count) to the persistent Redis
 DB
- The app runs two microservices, the first one encapsulates Tomcat, which runs Spring application. The second microservice runs a Redis instance
- CircleCI pipeline builds the app (frontend with Webpack and backend with Maven) and deploys it to the remote Swarm cluster
- Full project overview is available on GitHub README.md